DAVID HOUSEKNECHT

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Phone: 607-483-9828

E-mail: david.j.houseknecht@gmail.com

Website: https://djhouseknecht.github.io/

PROFILE

I am a full stack developer at Liberty University with 3 years coding experience. The current half of my experience has been developing enterprise level web applications for over 100,000 users consisting of university students, faculty, staff, and community members.

SKILLS

- JavaScript with specializations in Angular 6+ and Aurelia frameworks
- Java RESTful APIs utilizing Java Spring
- PL/SQL and MySQL databases
- PHP RESTful APIs utilizing Laravel
- HTML, CSS, and the SCSS preprocessor
- Docker to implement Continuous Integration and Deployment (CI/CD)
- Agile team work environment

EDUCATION

BS INTERDISCIPLINARY STUDIES

Liberty University Online (Jan. 2014 - Dec. 2018)

- Computer Science
- Business Administration

EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

IT Development - Liberty University (Aug. 2017 - Present)

- Construct User Interfaces using JavaScript, HTML, SCSS, and the JavaScript frameworks Angular and Aurelia
- Develop RESTful APIs using Java Spring and the PHP Laravel framework
- Work using an Agile approach to communicate with other developers, management, and designers to produce the best possible results
- Write comprehensive build plans to test and package applications using Docker for Continuous Integration and Deployment (CI/CD)
- Manage and manipulate data with PL/SQL and MySQL databases

TECHNICAL SPECIALIST

Student Financial Services - Liberty University (Oct. 2016 - Aug. 2017)

- Create applications using C#, MySQL, Visual Basics (VBA), and the MS Suite to increase efficiency in processing data for an office of 400+ employees
- Analyze daily processes and offer suggestions to increase efficiency
- Troubleshoot office computers, phones, and other technical issues

GRANTS PROCESSOR II

Financial Aid - Liberty University (May 2015 - Oct. 2016)

- Utilize Visual Basic (VBA) programming to streamline daily processes and reports for a team of processors (12-18 employees)
- Perform Professional Judgement on a case-by-case basis for students that fall outside of the normal processes defined by the Dept. of Ed.
- Audit Federal Applications for Federal Student Aid (FAFSA)